<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Rachel Thomas</title><link>http://racheltho.github.io/</link><description>Data science</description><atom:link href="http://racheltho.github.io/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 14:16:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola &lt;http://getnikola.com/&gt;</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>true confessions</title><link>http://racheltho.github.io/posts/true-confessions.html</link><description>&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h1 id="true-confessions"&gt;true confessions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id="of-degenerate-debugging"&gt;of degenerate debugging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my head, I know good techniques for debugging, but time after time, my heart leads me astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style="list-style-type: decimal"&gt;&lt;li&gt;isolate the bug to the simplest test case I can find&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when doing something new, make minor and incremental changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;step through my code slowly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;and most importantly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;don't just flail around making random changes based on my random hypotheses about what the problem is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for some reason, I always think "this time is different". I know what my mistake must be, and I'll just change it and re-run. No, that's not it, let me change something else. I can make big changes to my algorithm at the same time I massively scale up and change the input source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debugging</category><guid>http://racheltho.github.io/posts/true-confessions.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 13:21:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Starting My Blog</title><link>http://racheltho.github.io/posts/starting-my-blog.html</link><description>&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h1 id="getting-started"&gt;Getting started&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id="if-you-are-reading-this-then-i-have-succeeded"&gt;if you are reading this, then I have succeeded&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step to starting a blog was choosing a platform. I was pretty sure I wanted to use ipython notebook, having found some recent inspiration from Brian Granger's &lt;a href="https://github.com/ellisonbg/talk-strata-sc2014"&gt;Strata Talk&lt;/a&gt; and Cam Davidson-Pilon's &lt;a href="http://nbviewer.ipython.org/github/CamDavidsonPilon/Probabilistic-Programming-and-Bayesian-Methods-for-Hackers/blob/master/Prologue/Prologue.ipynb"&gt;Bayesian Methods for Hackers book&lt;/a&gt; (neither of these are blogs, but they are both awesome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ipython notebook is not a platform. Google revealed a few options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use nbconvert to convert ipynb to html and then put on blogger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://getnikola.com/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt; static site generator and put on &lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried them both: http://datarachel.blogspot.com/ and http://racheltho.github.io/ (although you can probably guess which won if you are on this site).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="on-getting-set-up"&gt;On getting set up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For blogger: I had been using the dev version of ipython, and nbconvert doesn't seem to work properly there. Once I realized the problem, I installed version 1.0 and everything was fine. I copied and pasted the html manually into the input box provided by blogger, which seemed a bit clunky (couldn't find a direct upload, but maybe it's out there??)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Nikola/gh-pages: Nikola was pretty simple to set up, but I was initially confused about what went in my racheltho.github.io repo. I eventually discovered that I wanted to push my output/ folder (created by Nikola) and this seemed to work well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="my-thoughts"&gt;My thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nikola pages definitely have a much cleaner look and better layout. To be fair, I didn't try different themes for either, but I am pleased with how much Nikola provides automatically. I also like the interface with GitHub Pages. Since I already use git regularly and like the version control it provides, this was another bonus. The Nikola handbook offers a compelling argument for the &lt;a href="http://getnikola.com/handbook.html#why-static"&gt;benefits of static pages&lt;/a&gt;. All in all, the choice was straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://racheltho.github.io/posts/starting-my-blog.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 14:50:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>